A Guide to the Margaret (Peggy) Cochrane Architectural Collection, 1951-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Margaret (Peggy) Cochrane Architectural Collection, 1951-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2013-088
13.2 cu. ft.
Margaret (Peggy) Cochrane Architectural Collection includes drawings for approximately 70 professional projects. Project drawings vary in size and detail, and most are residential projects in Southern California.
Cochrane, Margaret Ann
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Margaret (Peggy) Cochrane Architectural Collection was donated to the International Archive of Women in Architecture by the creator in 2012.
Biographical note
Margaret (Peggy) Ann Cochrane graduated with a B.A. Degree from Scripps College in Claremont, CA. There she majored in architecture, assisted in teaching and won the architecture prize her senior year. She did graduate work in architecture at the University of Southern California and in Columbia University in New York, and studied Architecture and City Planning in Europe (1954). Cochrane had over thirty years of varied experience in all types of construction: office buildings, schools, hospitals, factories, apartment houses, condominiums, housing tracts, custom residential and remodeling.
Some selected firms she has worked for include Kahn and Jacobs (New York, NY); Litchfield, Whiting, Panero, and Severud (Tehran, Iran); Daniel, Mann, Johnson, and Mendenhall (Los Angeles, CA); and the Department of Public Buildings City of Los Angeles. She operated her own practice from March 1959-June 1963 and from February 1978 to the end of her career.
Cochrane died in 2012.
Scope and Content
The Margaret (Peggy) Cochrane Architectural Collection includes drawings for approximately 70 professional projects. Project drawings vary in size and detail, and most are residential projects in Southern California.
Arrangement
The Margaret (Peggy) Cochrane Architectural Collection is arranged by type of construction: Additions, Apartment Complexes, Remodels, Residences, and Miscellaneous.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Architecture; History of Women in Architecture; International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA)
Genre and Form Terms:
Architectural drawings.
Contents List
- Professional Papers
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Planning Civic Design by Charles J. Salinas (Box-folder 1:2)
- Project Records
  - Drawings
    - Additions
      - [3269] Mr. and Mrs. J. Paul de Grasse ( Los Angeles, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [4187] Mr. Ramiro Salazar ( Pacoima, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [6160] Mr. and Mrs. Irvine Somers ( Los Angeles, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [6181] Mr. and Mrs. Howard Sargent ( Los Angeles, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:6, Box 5)
      - [7175] Marilyn Corrigan ( Sylmar, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [7166] Mr. Harlod Felix ( Los Angeles, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [7180] Mr. and Mrs. Joe Curcio ( Pacoima, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [7184] Mr. and Mrs. Jaime Sanchez ( Mission Hills, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [8185] Mr. and Mrs. Alex Musser ( Reseda, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - [9175] Mr. and Mrs. Robert Walla ( Los Angeles, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - Mr. and Mrs. James Adamiak ( N Hollywood, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - Mr. and Mrs. J.M. Lindauer ( Encino, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - J & N Sheppard ( Los Angeles, CA; duplex addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Richard Stark ( Woodland Hills, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Dennis Venizelos ( Woodland Hills, CA; addition ) [Dr] (Box 5)
    - Apartments
      - [213] 27 Unit Apartments ( Encino, CA; apartments ) [Dr] (Box 6)
      - [472] Beverly Glen Apts ( Los Angeles, CA, 12/2/1972; apartments ) [Dr] (Box 10)
      - [6270] 12 Unit Apartment House ( Pasadena, CA; apartments ) [Dr] (Box 10)
      - [68040] 508 Unit Apartment Project ( Los Angeles, CA, 5/16/1969; apartments ) [Dr] (Box 12, Box 9)
      - 4 Unit Condominium, Orange Grove (Pasadena, CA; apartments) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:9)
      - 16 Unit Apartment Building (apartments) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:9)
      - 20 Unit Apartment ( N Hollywood, CA; apartments ) [Dr] (Box 10)
      - Mr. Harold Newton ( Pasadena, CA, 5/13/1970; Co-Op Apartments ) [Dr] (Box 11)
    - Remodels
      - [210] Mrs. Majorie McKnight ( remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [1162] Mr. and Mrs. H. Friedmann (Los Angeles, CA; remodel) [Dr, Ms] (Box-folder 1:6)
      - [1261] Mr. and Mrs. Robert Hebl ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [1275] Mr. and Mrs. John Henry ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - [3163] Mr. and Mrs. F. Lee Woodard ( Pico Rivera, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - [3178] Mr. and Mrs. R. Palmer Reed ( Marina del Rey, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [3180] Mr. Dennis Dvorin ( Brentwood, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [3186] Mr. and Mrs. Robert Ross ( Encino, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - [4177] Mr. and Mrs. Melvin Albert ( Woodland Hills, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 2)
      - [4183] Mr. Leo Olmos ( Pacioma, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - [4592] Mr. and Mrs. R.L. Sheppard (Beverly Hills, CA; remodel) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:8)
      - [4593] Mrs. Shirley Strozer (Beverly Hills, CA; apt. remodel) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:8)
      - [5190] Mr. and Mrs. Robert Zema (Sylmar, CA, 5/26/1990; remodel) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [5763] Mr. and Mrs. Weasley Johnston (Manhattan Beach, CA, 12/9/1963; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [6179] Mr. and Mrs. V.M. Chamberes ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [8161] Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Sworski ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - [8175] Mr. and Mrs. Howard Miller ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - [10180] Mr. and Mrs. R. Rice ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 5, Box 4)
      - [11180] Mrs. Virginia Morales ( Pasadena, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
        - (Box 4)
      - [11380] Mr. Neil Hartley ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:9, Box 4)
      - [12281] Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Medina ( Canoga Park, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Charles Finkel ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - Mr. Keith Kennedy ( Tarzana, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Michael Lock ( La Cañada, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Emmanuel Phillips / 83171 ( Palos Verdes Estate, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Barry Pollack ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 4)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Allen Turner ( Los Angeles, CA; remodel ) [Dr] (Box 3)
    - Residences
      - [201] Mr. and Mrs. James F. Bell ( Manhattan Beach, CA, 2/19/1951; residence ) [Dr] (Box 7)
      - [1179] Mr. Sydney Grobstein ( Reseda, CA, 10/16/1990; residence ) [Dr] (Box 12, Box 8)
      - [2481] Mr. and Mrs. L.M. Purcell ( Redondo Beach, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 2, Box 12)
      - [3261] Mr. Arthur E. MacBeth ( Los Angeles, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 7, Box-folder 1:9)
      - [4175] Mr. and Mrs. Gary Osborn ( Fairview Palace, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 7)
      - [4591] Mr. and Mrs. George A. Moran ( Tulare, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 2, Box-folder 1:3, Box-folder 1:5, Box-folder 1:6, Box 12)
      - [4601] Mrs. M.C. Bowman ( Los Angeles, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 2)
      - [6171] Mr. and Mrs. Tom Kelley ( W Los Angeles, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 2)
      - [6611 ] Mr. and Mrs. Burton Slatkin ( Beverly Hills, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 7)
      - [7159] Mr. and Mrs. Dennis Levine ( Pasadena, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:3, Box 2, Box-folder 1:5)
      - [10260] Miss L.V. Parrott ( residence ) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:3, Box-folder 1:5, Box 2)
      - [70924] Mr. and Mrs. McCune ( Hollywood, CA, 3/17/1977; residence ) [Dr] (Box 8)
      - (Box 7)
      - Mr. and Mrs. John French ( Los Angeles, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:5, Box 2, Box-folder 1:9)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Donald Gerson ( Hidden Hills, CA; residence ) [Dr] (Box 2)
      - Dolores Wittke (CA, 9/27/1973; vacation house) [Dr] (Box-folder 1:3, Box 2, Box-folder 1:5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - [440B] Villa San Dimas (Bakesfield, CA; details) [Dr] (Box 8)
      - [1313] San Gabriel High School (Alhambra, CA, July 1953; High School) [Dr] (Box 12, Box-folder 1:4, Box 10)
      - [2181] Mr. Jack Berlin (Los Angeles, CA; walk in refrigerator) [Dr] (Box 9)
      - [3283] 50/50 Shadow Hills (9/1/1983) [Dr] (Box 9)
      - [5161] Mr. and Mrs. Robert Felburg (Los Angeles, CA; fallout shelter) [Dr] (Box 8)
      - [5280] Mr. Richard Morel (Reseda, CA; Cabaña) [Dr] (Box 11)
      - [7170] Mr. and Mrs. Martin Schaffer (Santa Monica, CA; Patio Enclosure) [Dr] (Box 11)
      - [11181] Mr. Manuel Perches (N Hollywood, CA; garage and storage) [Dr] (Box 9)
      - Four Year College (Box-folder 1:5, Box-folder 1:8)
      - Projects done with C. N. Aldrich of Long Beach, CA (Box 12)
    - Blue Prints (Box 12)
  - Project Files
    - Client List, Personal Practice (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Photographs (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Portfolios (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Project Files, Personal Practice (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Project List, Architectural Firms (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Sketches (2 folders) (Box-folder 1:9, Box-folder 1:8)